[Music]
haagen-dazs
chocolate peanut butter it's not a
flavor we can get in the uk but it's a
big or used to be a big popular flavour
in the us
until you start looking at the reviews
and the last couple of years they
obviously changed the recipe
i don't know what from and two but a lot
of people are unhappy about it
it's quite a simple recipe to make so
let's just show you how to do it at home
[Music]
the actual ice cream base is really easy
just put all your ingredients in the pan
and gently heat it
to melt the chocolate and disperse your
cocoa powder once that's done take it
off the heat and store in the fridge for
at least four hours
one thing that the us customers really
hated was haagen-dazs removing the big
lumps of peanut butter from the original
i've popped a plate in the freezer
and i'm just gonna nicely dollop some
lumps of peanut butter on the plate and
pop them in the freezer
[Music]
the peanut butter swirl is something
people struggle to get right
and that's because it goes hard when you
freeze it in ice cream
to get around that you need to make a
xylitol simple syrup
so put your xylitol and your water in a
pan and then reduce it down
just like any simple syrup reduce it by
half it just won't go as thick as a
normal cane sugar
simple syrup once that's ready put your
peanut butter in there and give it a
really good stir
and then pop it in a container ready to
use 20 minutes before you want to churn
your ice cream take it out the fridge
and add two tablespoons of milk powder
you know i love my milk problem
this will give it a slightly better
consistency if you store it in the
freezer for a long period of time
it's a stabilizer essentially
when your ice cream is ready start
loading in your tub
you'll just layer it like any other ice
cream and then when it's finished pop it
in the freezer
so the ice cream has been in the freezer
for i don't know six seven hours
something like that
we're gonna get it straight out get some
dished up and see what it looks like
another great tub design for my wife
this is the perfect marriage between
peanut butter and chocolate if you like
the tubs
let us know a lot of people like these
on on reddit so um yeah let us know what
you think about these
[Music]
there you go looks great texture's good
it's basically the same ice cream as the
hydrogen's belgian chocolate so i'll put
a link up here so you can actually go
and see that one very very similar kind
of process to make but this one
obviously has some nice chunks of
peanut butter you get the swell of
peanut butter and
the peanut butter chunk
i love peanut butter my wife hates it so
this tub is all mine
i think the problem that people had
was that those chunks of peanut butter
were just totally missing
and the haagen-dazs were just sending
tubs of chocolate ice cream out i mean
if you buy a tub of chocolate ice cream
expecting that then great but
chocolate peanut butter should be a
really good mix
and at least doing this you're in
control of how much you put in
and i've loaded this with with peanut
butter it's a really luxurious belgian
chocolate whatever belgian chocolate you
use is absolutely fine just just
use what's available to you the most
important part is
how you disperse it into that base just
make sure that it's really
well melted dissolved that cocoa powder
really does need to be whisked in
really really well once you've done that
you're good to go it's a classic
combination that
i love i just wish over the years i
could have bought it in the shops but
hey i can make my own now and so can you
if this is a flavor you've had yourself
the hargenars version
and it changed let us know how it
changed why it changed and what you felt
about it and
hopefully try and make this one and let
me know what you think about this one
anyway
thanks very much for watching hope you
like and subscribe and we'll see you
next week when we're doing an avengers
ice cream